RG 014, Department of Banking
Connecticut State Library
- Series 2. Incorporation Files and Special Charters, circa 1913-1957; 4 cubic feet
  - Waterbury Trust Company (Box 101)
    Merged with and into the Connecticut National Bank, Bridgeport, 1957 May 10.
  - Watertown Trust Company (Box 101)
    Merged with and into the Colonial Trust Company, Waterbury, 1951 June 1.
  - Watson Trust Company, Bridgeport (Box 101)
    Never conducted actual business. Charter repealed 1923 October 1.
  - West Hartford Bank and Trust Company, Organized under General Law.; Name changed to West Hartford Trust Company 1926 February 15. Merged with and into the Hartford Connecticut Trust Company, 1946 September 16. (Box 101)
  - West Hartford Trust Company, Organized under General Law.; Application denied on 1925 December 7 due to the fact that a charter was granted to the West Hartford Bank and Trust Company on or about that time, and there didn't seem to be a need for two banks. (Box 101)
  - West Haven Bank and Trust Company (Box 101)
    Home Bank and Trust Company, West HAven, merged with and into the West Haven Bank and Trust Companyu on 1931 March 28. The latter bank closed on 1931 December 23.
  - West Side Bank & Trust Company, Hartford (Box 101)
  - Westville Bank and Trust Company, New Haven (Box 101)
    Authority granted on 1930 February 8. Bank never operated and authority to do so expired on 1932 June 6.
  - Westville Bank and Trust Company, New Haven (Box 101)
    Notice of intention to organize filed on 1926 March 11, but organization was never completed.
  - Wethersfield Bank and Trust Company (Box 101)
    Merged with and into the Hartford Connecticut Trust Company on 1933 December 26.
  - Windsor Trust Company (Box 101)
    Incorporated under name of the Windsor Trust and Safe Deposit Company, name being changed to Windsor Trust Company on 1925 February 20. Merged with and into the Hartford National Bank and Trust Company, 1956 December 14.
  - Winsted Trust Company (Box 101)
    Did not actually operate. Charter repealed 1923 October 1.
- Series 3. Bank Returns, 1865-1896; 1.5 cubic feet
  - Bank returns, 1896; 1 volume (4 inches) (Box 102)
    Annual Statements (form returns) as filed by Connecticut banks.
  - Bank Commissioner's correspondence, 1865; 1 folder (Box 102)
    Fragmentary. Five items pertaining to submission of annual reports of banks.
    Found with Tolland Savings Bank records.
  - Bank Commissioner's annual report, circa 1868; 1 folder (Box 102)
    Handwritten report to the General Assembly by Bank Commissioner Thomas Cowles of Farmington.
  - Unidentified ledger book, circa 1900-1930; 1 volume (Box Item)
- Series 4. Press Releases, 1997-2011
  - 2016-014, .25 cubic feet
    Shared box with Accession: 2016-024.
    - Press releases, 1997-2011 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
- Series 5. Commissioners Files, 1992-2005
  - 2016-024, .25 cubic feet
    Shared box with Accession: 2016-014.
    - Correspondence - Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) regulations and foreign broker-dealers transaction exemptions, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence - security deposit interest, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Testimony of Ralph A. Lambiase, Director, Division of Securities, Connecticut Department of Banking and President North American Securities Administrators Association, Inc. before the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, United States Senate, "The Role of State Securities Regulators in Protecting Investors", 2004 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Office of the Comptroller of the Currency (OCC) preemption, 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 6)